Mudit Gupta

29-A, Dayanand Colony, Tonk Road, Jaipur, Rajasthan

EDUCATION

B.Tech August, 2014 — 2018

IIT Hyderabad

SUMMARY

I am a student of IIT Hyderabad pursuing B.Tech in Engineering Science and a passionate Programmer, A Techy Geek, Developer and an Explorer and interested in Product Management. Worked on projects related to React.js, node.js, Android, java, data analysis, Machine Learning etc. Also worked as Marketing Coordinator for our fest. I like to explore and try out various things and so in turn lean a lot of things and a big fan of American T.V. Series, watched a lot of them. Right now working as a Manager for our fest and also E-Cell Manager. In the tech field right now working on Machine learning.

WORK EXPERIENCE

IIT Hyderabad

April 2016 — present

E-Cell Manager

Leading the startup culture at IIT Hyderabad · I conduct various events, workshops, interactive games and speaker sessions for inspiring and assisting young entrepreneurs in their journey in the world of business. I assist them by providing support in terms of resources, networking, guidance, and motivation

Nvision 2016 April 2016 — present

Hospitality, Workshops and Infra Manager

- Leading a team of 4 Coordinators and around 100 volunteers.
- Taking care of Workshops Deals.
- Taking care of Finances and Marketing Deals for Sponsorship.
- Taking care of Hospitality and Infrastructure during fest and Workshops.
- Ensuring smooth running of Fest.
- Managing with Faculties.

Carrot ID

December 2015 — March 2015

Developer

- Made a website with Dynamic front-end using React.
- For Data flow i initially used Reflux and then moved on to redux.
- React Router for routing.
- Used various react implementations like React Code Mirror, React TreeBeard etc.

- Used SuperAgent for ajax requests.
- Followed Agile Development Process
- Used Hapi.js and MongoDb for Backend

DYDE

September 2015 — November 2015

Android App and website front end developer

- Made a static website using bootstrap, maichimp etc.
- Made front end of Android app using XML and Java in Android Studio. Used various layouts and views.
- App was a social networking platform where you can challenge your friends with various tasks.

Nvision 2016

June 2015 — April 2016

Marketing Co-ordinator

- Talk and convince various companies to sponsor our fest.
- Leaded a team of 10 people and trained them.
- Took care of the requirements of our sponsors for various publicity like online publicity and ground publicity.
- Coordinated with other coordinators and managers for managing the event according to the requirements of our sponsors.

Hunger Torrent

August 2015 — October 2015

Co-Founder

Co-Founded Hunger torrent as food delivery service which was operational at IIT Hyderabad for 2 months. Problem - As IIT Hyderabad is in outskirts of Hyderabad so there are no food outlets and Hostel food anyway sucks so for tasty food we have to travel for around 1-2 hours one way journey.

Solution we thought of - Many times some students travel to and fro city for some work so there will be an online portal where students will order the food from the outlet lying in the way back of the student which was in city and that student will collect the food from the outlet and deliver it to us, in return he will get some percent money extra let's say 30% which will be charged from the customer.

PROJECTS

• Meteor Starter Kit (https://github.com/mudit1403/Zen) - Made a meteor - react - react router starter kit and for the demo of that starter kit i made login and registration page using that kit.

Key Concepts Demonstrated -

React with Meteor

Basic routing with React Router

Routes requiring authentication

Working with reactive data

• IDENTIFY FRAUD FROM ENRON EMAIL (https://github.com/mudit1403/Machine-Learning-Python)
-Identifying Enron Employees who may have committed fraud based on the public Enron financial and email dataset.

Key Concepts Demonstrated -

1. ML Algorithms - naive_bayes, decision tree, svm

- 2. Regression
- 3. k means
- 4. feature selection
- 5. pca, etc.
- Titanic Data Analysis (https://github.com/mudit1403/Titanic-Machine-Learning) Looking at socio-economic status, gender, and age, predict who's and who's not survive the Titanic using Python & Random Forests.

Key Concepts Demonstrated -

- 1. Numpy, Pandas
- 2. Random Forest Using Sklearn
- 3. Data Cleaning
- Made a multi-terrine bot which can work both as a car and a helicopter.
- Made a 3-D model of play house in solid edge and 3-D printed it.

SKILLS

- Languages C, C++, Python, Java, Javascript, Fortran
- WebBased Languages HTML, CSS, JS
- o Database Management, PostgreSQL, MongoDb
- Rest API, GraphQL
- Frameworks and Libraries React.js, Reflux, Redux, Meteor, Node.js, Hapi, Express
- Android App Development XML, Java, React Native
- Machine Learning, Data Analysis
- Data Structures
- Solid Edge
- MATLAB, Octave
- Marketing
- Git

ONLINE COURSES DONE

Programming Languages - Udacity

Intro to Machine Learning, Intro to Data Analysis - Udacity

Android Development for Beginners, Developing Android Apps - Udacity

Programming Foundations with Python - Udacity

Intro to Descriptive Statistics, Intro to Inferential Statistics - Udacity

Machine Learning (Stanford University) - Coursera

 $Server-side\ Development\ with\ Node Js\ (The\ Hong\ Kong\ University\ of\ Science\ and\ Technology)-Coursera$

Introduction to Software Product Management (University of Alberta) - Coursera

INTERESTS

My interests include

• Learning new things and gaining new experiences.

- Entrepreneurship.
- Developing new things.
- Product Management
- Playing billiards, snooker.

VOLUNTEERING

worked as a volunteer in the following domains:-

nss - worked as a volunteer for teaching activities, etc. for social cause

Finance - Took care of finances of the fest.

Infi - organised an event named complete 4 to win more during ELAN (Cultural Fest of IIT-H).

Hospi - guest hospitality and handled registration desk.